Danielle Taulman

132 Hazelwood Ct. Gastonia, NC 28056 704-691-5680

dtaul2017@gmail.com
http://dtaul2017.wixsite.com/mysite

Objective

My goal would be to utilize my skills and expand my experiences I have gained at libraries and other administrative facilities. My intent is to help staff members and students function in a productive, resourceful, and organized manner. To further expand my knowledge and abilities at this field of service will not only increase a library's administrative department's values, but, my own value as well.

Education

University of North Carolina at Greensboro (UNCG), Greensboro, NC *Masters Degree in Library Science*, GPA: 4.0

December 2021

University of North Carolina at Charlotte (UNCC), Charlotte, NC *Bachelor of Arts in History*, GPA: 3.4

May 2017

Gaston College

Associate of the Arts, GPA: 3.3

December 2014

Library Experience

J. Murrey Atkins Library, UNC-Charlotte, Charlotte, NC

Jan. 2017-May 2017

Digitization Assistant for Oral Histories

- Edited and reviewed oral history transcripts from certain periods of time in North Carolina for online reference records and research tabs
- Researched and analyzed history for reference purposes

Gastonia Public Library, Gastonia, NC

Oct. 2013-Mar.2015

Library Assistant and Student Programs

- Organized student programs with the Children's Librarian for the children to enjoy
- Volunteered at the Circulation Desk in shelving, weeding, and shifting books
- Assisted patrons in finding their resources through the computer or guiding them to the right location of materials.

York County Public Library, Rock Hill, SC

Jan. 2014-Dec. 2014

Library Assistant

• Shelved, weeded, and shifted books

Teaching Experience

H.H. Beam Elementary School, Gastonia, NC

Jan. 2020-Present

Reading Literacy A.S.P.I.R.E. Tutor

- Creating Lesson Plans
- Tutor 14 kindergarteners with reading literacy skills such as reading, pronunciation, and writing
- Helping them with their homework

Parkwood Baptist Church, Gastonia, NC

Jan. 2013-Present

Childcare and Youth Counselor

- Providing child service once a week
- Leading youth activities, responsible for youths' safety, conduct, and teachings

Woodhill Elementary School, Gastonia, NC

Oct. 2017-June 2018

2nd Grade Teacher Assistant and Tutor

- Assisted students by tutoring them in their reading and math skills
- Planned curriculum with teachers

- Organized classroom libraries
- Established student behavioral program rewarding responsible behavior
- Substituted classes when teachers are out

Customer Service Related Experience

TJ Maxx, Gastonia, NC

June 2012- Present

Customer Relations Employee

- Providing great customer service to shoppers by assisting with their transactions at the cash registers, jewelry counters, and the dressing room
- Assisting in training new employees

Clubs

National Society of Leadership and Success

2016-2017

This is a leadership honor society that recognizes college students based on their academics to identify and achieve their goals for the future.

Gamma Beta Phi Honors

2013-2014

This is an honor society that recognizes a student's academics and requires community service as a leadership quality.

Youth Services

Getaway Summer Camp and 180 Weekend

Youth Leader, Parkwood Baptist Church, Gastonia, NC

2013-Present

Vacation Bible School

Kids Leader, Parkwood Baptist Church, Gastonia, NC

2012-2014

Skills

Computer Skills: Windows 10, Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Excel

References

Rita Johnston
Digital Production Librarian
UNC-Charlotte J. Murrey Atkins Library, Reference
9201 University City Boulevard
Charlotte, NC 28223
704-687-8622
rjohn211@uncc.edu

Tanya Jones Gastonia Public Library Supervisor 1555 East Garrison Boulevard Gastonia, NC 28054 704-868-2164

tanya.jones@gastongov.com

LeAnne Conyers
Site Coordinator for A.S.P.I.R.E.
H.H. Beam Elementary
200 Davis Park Rd.
Gastonia, NC, 28052
704-860-2891
lwconyers@gaston.k12.nc.us

Jeffrey Jones TJ Maxx Manager 415 Cox Rd. Gastonia, NC 28054 jef00105@tjx.com